Pesotta, Rose Photographs 5928 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Rose Pesotta Photographs
1934-1950
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Pesotta, Rose
5928 P
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Photographs.
7527795
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 10, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 10, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Born Rakhel Peisoty in Derazhnia, Ukraine in 1896 to grain merchants, Pesotta was well educated and influenced by the Narodnaya Volya (People's Will), and eventually adopted anarchist views.
Pesotta emigrated to New York City at the age of 17 (1913), and found employment in a shirtwaist factory, she joined the ILGWU very soon after. The ILGWU was a union that represented mostly Jewish and Latina female garment workers. She was elected to the all male executive board of ILGWU Local 25 in 1920. Pesotta went to Brookwood Labor College for two years in the 1920s.
In 1933 the union sent her to Los Angeles to organize the garment workers there. The organizing of the Mexican immigrant garment workers lead to the Los Angeles Garment workers Strike of 1933. As a result of this success, she was made vice-president of the union in 1934.
In 1944, she resigned from the executive board of the union in protest of the fact that, despite 85% of the union's memebership were women, she was the sole female executive member.
Rose Pesotta died in 1965.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Pesotta, Rose, 1896-1965.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
7527795
- Akron-Flint-Detroit (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Atlantic City, Atlantic Voyage, 1937-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Book Signing Parties (Box 2, Folder 3a)
- Boston (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Brookwood (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Brookwood (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Brookwood (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Bryn Mawr (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Brookwood (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Chicago (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dubinsky and family (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Fleshine (Mollie Steimer and husband Senya) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- General (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Israel, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Los Angeles (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Los Angeles (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Mohegan (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Montreal and Canada (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Monney, Tom -- Warren K. Billings (Box 2, Folder 19)
- New York and Personal (Box 2, Folder 20)
- New York and Personal (Box 2, Folder 21)
- New York and Personal (Box 2, Folder 22)
- New York and Personal (Box 2, Folder 23)
- New York and Personal (Box 2, Folder 24)
- New York and Personal (Box 2, Folder 25)
- New York and Personal (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Ohio, Cleveland (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Peterson, Esther; family/Ed Allen family; Bill Kennseley? (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Joseph Turnbold Monument (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Scope and Contents
  7 photographs
- Misc. photos, negatives and letters (Box 2, Folder 30)
  9 photographs
- Photos from a small photo album (Box 2, Folder 31)
  15 photographs
- Misc. photos (some have labels) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  26 photographs
- Misc. photos (some with labels) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  28 photographs
- Polish photos, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Polish photos, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Polish photos, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Puerto Rico, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Puerto Rico, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Puerto Rico, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Rocker, Berkman, Havel, Tom, Bill, Shane? (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Seattle (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Stelton (Box 3, Folder 9)
- USSR (Box 3, Folder 10)
- USSR (Box 3, Folder 11)
- USSR (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Unity (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Unity (Box 3, Folder 14)
- negatives; slides - some labeled (Box 3, Folder 15)
  16 slides
- Negatives (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Movie Film - B&W - Cat Statue (Box 3, Folder 17)